

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

# STEPHEN **THOMAS**

# **PROFILE**

I'm a Front-End Developer and Creative. Having designed websites as a teenager, I later spent time mastering every kind of writing there is. I've now rekindled my love for coding and have expanded my skillset with tools such as CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React, and Firebase. I focus on creating dynamic and intuitive and accessible web experiences and commit to writing clean, reusable and semantic code.

# **FEATURED PROJECTS**

# DETECTIVE POKÉMON (Live | Code) - React | REST API | Sass

• A guiz game built in React that lets users select the best Pokemon to solve a crime. Coordinates data from the London police API with the Pokemon API for a seamless user experience

# THE COVID STORE (Live | Code) - JavaScript | Sass | jQuery

• A mock-up of an eCommerce store that sells everything you might need in a 2020-era pandemic. It has a fully-functioning shopping cart that updates as you click, which also triggers updates to the store's displayed inventory count.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **COPYWRITER**

Innovate USA, 2019-2020

• I wrote profiles of entrepreneurs and startup founders for a series of B2B books. I personally interviewed each entrepreneur and wrote a) a profile on them, and b) a first-person think-piece with them.

## **CO-CREATOR**

"Miss Misery", 2017-2020

• I was one of two co-creators of a fictional web series about open relationships. Over 3 years, my co-creator and I led a core team of 5 people in creating an 80-minute fictional web series that won Best Script at the British Web Awards on a budget of \$25,000. Writing, directing, producing, fundraising — and acting! — duties shared.

## CREATIVE WRITING PROFESSOR

George Brown College, 2015-2018

- · I taught Autobiographical Writing to adult students. I received consistently excellent feedback, and updated all syllabi to reflect contemporary diversity values.
- I also rewrote much of the college's entire course calendar, based on extensive faculty interviews.

# CONTACT

stevecodes.co

stevekwthomas@gmail.com

1 (205) 928-3934

github.com/stevekwt

linkedin.com/in/stephen-thomasb5915344/

# **SKILLS**



**j**Query

































REST

Accessibility Design APIs

# Сору Writing

JavaScript

# **EDUCATION**

# Juno College of Technology

- Web Development Immersive Bootcamp Certificate, Fall 2020
- Continuing Education JavaScript Course, Fall 2020
- Continuing Education Web Development Course, Fall 2020

# University of Alabama

• Master of Fine Arts, Creative Writing, 2014

# **University of Toronto**

• BA, Cognitive Science, 2008